Test 3
This is the Ielts listening test.
You will hear a number of different recordings and you will have to answer questions on what you hear.
There will be time for you to read the instructions and questions and you will have a chance to check your work.
All the recordings will be played once only.
The test is in four parts.
At the end of the test you will be given 10 minutes to transfer your answers to the answer sheet.
No turn to part one.
Part one
You will hear a woman who works at an employment agency talking to a man about jobs he could apply for.
First, you have some time to look at questions one to five.
Now listen carefully and answer questions one to five.
Good morning. Thanks for coming in to see us here at the agency . I'm one of the agency representatives and my name is Sally Baker.
Hi Sally, I think we spoke on the phone didn't we that's right. We did.
So, thank you for sending in your CV, we've had quite a careful look at it and I think we have two jobs that might be suitable for you.
OK, the first one, is in a company based in north London, there looking for an administrative assistant, OK.
What sort of company is it? They're called home solutions and they design and make furniture?
Oh I don't know much about that, but it sounds interesting.
yes. Well, as I said, they want someone in their office and looking at your past experience, it does look as if you fit quite a few of the requirements.
So on your CV it appears you've done some data entry.
Yes, so that's one skill they want. Then they expect the person there point to attend meetings and take notes there OK.
I've done that before. Yes, and you need to be able to cope with general admin. Filing and keeping records and so on, but that should be OK.
And in my last job, I also had to manage the diary.
Excellent! That's something they want here too. I'd suggest you add it to your CV.
I don't think you mentioned that. Did you? No.
So, as far as the requirements go, they want a good computer skills of course, and they particularly mention spreadsheets.
That should be fine. And interpersonal skills, which would be something they'd check with your references. I think that should be OK. Yes.
and then they mentioned that they want someone who is careful and takes care with details.
Just looking at your CV, I'd say you're probably all right there, I think so, yes!
Do they want any special experience? I think they wanted some experience of Teleconferencing. Oh, I've got three years experience of that.
Uh-huh, let's see, yes. Good. In fact there only asking for at least one year, so that's great. So is that something that might interest you? It is, yes.
The only thing is you said they were in north London, so it would be quite a long commute for me, OK?
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.
Now listen and answer questions 6 to 10.
So the second position might suit you better as far as the location goes at.
That's for a warehouse assistant, and that's in south London. Yes, that would be a lot closer,
And you've worked in a warehouse before, haven't you?
Yes, so as far as the responsibilities for this position, they want someone who could manage the stock obviously, and also deliveries.
That should be OK. You've got to keep track of stuff, but I've always been quite good with numbers.
Good, that their first requirement, and they want someone who is computer literate which we know you are. Sure.
And then they mention organizacional skills. They want someone who's well organized.
Yes, I think I am. And tidy? Yes, they go together really, don't they? Sure!
then the usual stuff, they want someone who can communicate well both orally and in writing, OK?
And for the last warehouse job I had, one of the things I enjoyed most was being part of a team.
I found that was really essential for the job.
Excellent, yes, they do mention that they want someone who's used to that, yes?
Now when you were working in a warehouse last time, what sorts of items were you dealing with?
It was mostly bathroom and kitchen equipment, sinks and stoves and fridges. So you're OK moving heavy things?
Sure, I'm quite strong, and I've had the training. Good!
Now. As far as experience goes, they mention they want someone with a license,
and that you have experience of driving in London. so you can cope with the traffic and so on.
Yes, no problem. and you've got experience of warehouse work.
And the final thing they mention is customer service. I think looking at your CV you're OK there, right? So what about pay? Can you tell me a bit more about that please?
That is the end of part one.
You now have one minute to check your answers to part one.