Test 4
This is the IELTS listening test.
You will hear a number of different recordings and you will have to answer questions on what you hear.
There will be time for you to read the instructions and questions and you will have a chance to check your work.
All the recordings will be played once only.
The test is in four parts.
At the end of the test you will be given 10 minutes to transfer your answers to the answer sheet.
Now, turn to part one.
Part one
You will hear a representative from a train company, talking to a woman about her train journey.
First, you have some time to look at questions one to six.
Now listen carefully and answer questions one to six.
Hello, do you mind if I ask you some questions about your journey today, we're doing a customer satisfaction survey.
Yes, OK. I've got about 10 minutes before my train home leaves. I'm on a day trip.
Great, thank you. So, first of all, could you tell me your name? It's Sophie Bird.
thank you. And would you mind telling me what you do?
I'm a journalist. Really? That must be interesting.
Yes, it is. So what's the reason for your visit here to the work.
Actually it's my day off. I came here to do some shopping. Oh, right.
But I do sometimes come here for work. OK. now, I'd like to ask some questions about your journey today. Is that OK? yes, no problem.
right, So can you tell me which station you're traveling back to? STAUNFIRTH where I live.
Uh, can I just check the spelling? STAUNFIRTH, That's right.
And you traveled from there this morning. Yes, OK, good.
Next, can I ask what kind of ticket you bought? I assume it wasn't a season ticket as you don't travel everyday.
That's right, no, I just got a normal return ticket.
I don't have a railcard, so I didn't get any discount. I keep meaning to get one because it's a lot cheaper.
Yes, you deceived 20% on your ticket today, so you paid the full price for your ticket. I paid 23.70 pounds.
OK. Do you think that's good value for money?
Not really, I think it's too much for a journey that only takes 45 minutes.
Yes, that's one of the main complaints we get, so you didn't buy your ticket in advance.
No, I know it's cheaper if you buy a week in advance, but I didn't know I was coming then.
I know you can't always plan ahead.
So did you buy it this morning? No, it was yesterday. right. And do you usually buy your tickets at the station?
Well, I do usually,but the ticket office closes early, and I hate using ticket machines.
I think ticket offices should be open for longer hours. There's always a queue for the machines and they're often out of order.
A lot of customers are seeing the same thing.
So to answer your question, I got an E ticket online.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 7 to 10.
And  answer questions 7 to 10.
OK, thank you, now. I'd like to ask you about your satisfaction with your journey.
So what would you say you were most satisfied with today?
Well, I like the Wi-Fi on the train. It's improved a lot. It makes it easier for me to work if I want to.
That's the first time today anyone's mentioned that. it's good to get some positive feedback on that. And is there anything you weren't satisfied with?
Well, normally the trains run on time and pretty reliable, but today there was a delay.
The train was about 15 minutes behind schedule.
That down! now, I'd also like to ask about the facilities at the station.
You probably notice that the whole stations been upgraded. What are you most satisfied with?
Oh, I think the best thing is that they've improved the amount of information about train times etc. That's given to passengers is much clearer.
Before there was only one board, and I couldn't always see it properly, which was frustrating. That's good. And is there anything you're not satisfied with?
let's say, I think things have generally improved a lot. The trains are much more modern and I like the new cafe.
But one thing is that there aren't enough places to sit down, especially on the platforms.
OK, so I'll put sitting down. Shall I ask the thing you're least satisfied with? Yes, OK?
Can I ask your opinion about some of the other facilities? We'd like feedback on whether people are satisfied, dissatisfied, or neither satisfied nor dissatisfied, OK?
But what about the parking at the station?
Well, to be honest, I don't really have an opinion as I never use it, so neither satisfied nor dissatisfied for that then. yes, I suppose so. OK, and what about these?
That is the end of part one.
You now have one minute to check your answers to part one.