Part 2
You will hear a woman giving a presentation about a holiday on an island in Britain that her company organizes.
First, you have some time to look at questions 11 to 14.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 14.
Good morning, my name is Erica Mathews and I'm the owner of Matthews Island Holidays, a company set up by my parents.
Thank you for coming to this presentation in which I hope to interest you in what we have to offer.
We are a small family run company, and we believe in the importance of the personal touch. so we don't aim to compete with other companies on the number of customers.
What we do is build on our many years experience, more than almost any other rail holiday company, to ensure we provide perfect Holidays in a small number of destinations which we've got to know extremely well.
I'll start with our 6 day: I love man holiday. This is a fascinating island in the Irish Sea, with Wales to the South, England to the East, Scotland to the north, and Northern Island to the West.
Our holiday starts in Heysham, where your tour manager will meet you.
Then you'll travel by ferry to the Isle of Man. Some people prefer to fly from Luton instead, and another popular option is to go by train to Liverpool and take a ferry from there.
You have five nights in the hotel ,and the price covers 5 breakfasts and dinners, and lunch on the three days when there are organized trips.
Day four is free and most people have lunch in a cafe or restaurant in Douglas.
The price of the holiday includes the ferry to the Isle of Man.
All travel on the island, the hotel, and the meals I've mentioned.
Incidentally, we tried to make booking our Holidays as simple and fair as possible.so unlike with many companies, the price is the same whether you book six months in advance or at the last minute, and there's no supplement for single rooms in hotels.
If you make a booking then need to change the start date, for example because of illness, you're welcome to change to an alternative date or a different tool for a small administrative fee.
Before you hear the rest of the talk, you have some time to look at questions 15 to 20.
Now listen and answer questions 15 to 20.
OK, So what does the holiday consist of?
Well, on day one you'll arrive in time for a short introduction by your tour manager, followed by dinner in the hotel.
The dining room looks out at the River close to where it flows into the harbor, and there's usually plenty of activity going on.
On day two, you'll take the coach to the small town of Peel on the way, calling in at that in world exhibition.
The Isle of Man isn't part of the United Kingdom, and it has its own Parliament called Tinwald.
It's claimed that this is the world's oldest parliament that still functioning and let it dates back to 979.
However, the earliest surviving reference to it is from 1422, so perhaps it isn't quite as old as it claims.
Day three, we have a trip to the mountains Snaefell. This begins with allegedly ride along the promenade in Douglas in a horse drawn tram.
Then you bought an electric train which takes you to the fishing village of Laxis.
From there it's an 8 kilometer ride in the Snaefell Mountain Railway to the top.
Lunch will be in the cafe giving you spectacular views of the island.
Day four is free view to explore using the pass, which will give you.
So you won't have to pay for travel on local transport, or for entrance to the islands heritage sites.
All you might just want to take it easy and Douglas and perhaps do a little light shopping.
The last full day day five is for some people the highlight of the holiday with a ride on the steam railway from Douglas to part Erin.
After some time to explore, a coach will take you to the headland that overlooks the calf of man, a small island just off the coast.
From there, you continue to Castle Town, which used to be the capital of the Isle of Man, and it's medieval Castle.
And on day six, it's back to the ferry. All the airport if you flew to the island and time to go home.
Now I'd like to tell you a bit more.
That is the end of Part 2.
You now have 30 seconds to check your answers to Part 2.