9 Tranquilizer
You are going to hear a talk about tranquilizers and sleeping pills which can cause problems.
Listen to the talk carefully and indicate whether the following statements are true or false . Write T for a statement which is true and F for a statement which is false.
Minor tranquilizers and sleeping pills are widely prescribed.
However, these drugs can cause problems, including memory loss and addiction .
Drug-induced unsteadiness can also lead to falls causing injuries .
Minor tranquilizer can be effective for short periods of time .
However, long-term use is often of limited value and introduces the risk of addiction and mental impairment.
Sleeping pills may help for a few days or a few weeks, but using them for more than one month generally causes more sleep problems than it solves .
If you have been taking minor tranquilizers or sleeping pills for a while , talk to your doctor about reevaluating your need for the medicine   or reducing your dosage.
Several kinds of adverse reactions can occur as a result of the medication side effects.
Side effects are predictable but unpleasant reactions to a drug.
They are usually mild, but they can be inconvenient.
In some cases, people get more serious allergies.
Some people have severe , sometimes life-threatening reactions called anaphylaxis to certain medications .
We should be aware that drugs are not necessarily the solution to every medical problem.
Not every illness can be effectively treated by a medication, so not all visits to your physician will necessarily result in a prescription.
For example, antibiotics are not effective against viral infections such as the common cold.
Consult your physician about alternative treatments for illnesses.
When talking to a physician or pharmacist , keep the lines of communication open.
Ask questions and answer their questions with as much detail and accuracy as possible.
This will help ensure that you receive quality health servers.
If you are prescribed medication , be sure to tell your physician and your pharmacist if you have ever had an allergic or unusual reaction to any medicine , food or other substance , or if you have been taking any other medication in the past few weeks.
If you have any doubt about a medication , be sure to consult your pharmacist .
Make the best use of any medication you are prescribed .
If directions are not followed , the medication will not work as effectively and may even be harmful.
Take all medications exactly as directed .
For example, "take with meals" means exactly that .
This is crucial to prevent stomach in irritation.
You should take all of your prescription .
Do not stop taking it as soon as you feel better.
The strongest bacteria are the last to die so if you don't take all of the medication , you may find the disease returning in a more severe form.
The following a basic guidelines for taking prescription and nonprescription medications:
Use medications only if non-drug approaches are not working.
Know the benefits and side effects of a medication before taking it .
Take the minimum effective dose .
Never take a drug prescribed for someone else.
Follow the prescription instructions exactly or let your doctor know why you didn't.
Keep medications in their original containers , and store them as directed .
Do not take medications in front of small children.
Prescription drugs are serious medications .
Do not share them with others and do not take anyone else's prescriptions.
There are no approved medications which can improve your intelligence .
Do not take so-called "smart pills" . They can be dangerous.