9 A Library Tour.
Listen to the guided tour commentary and label the places marked .
Choose from the box below . Write the appropriate letters in the diagram.
Welcome to the library tour.  You can see our library is a 4-storey building .
We'll begin our tour of the first level of library here at the entrance.
We'll go in a clockwise direction . Here is a map of the library that may help you.
The room facing us is the Catalogue section .
As you can see ,it's a computerized catalogue system and it's very easy to use.
On our left is the Loans and Return section.
There is a Circulation desk for borrowing and returning books.
Next to the Loans and Return section , you will see the section for newspapers and magazines.
The library has an extensive collection of local and international English language newspapers and magazines.
They are kept on those shelves for one month and then stored elsewhere.
As we continue our tour , in the far left corner, you will see a large room.
That is our Reference section .
As we know , reference texts cannot be borrowed for use outside the library ;
they must be used within the library , so you will say some nice seating area for you to read the books in this section.
In the far right corner is the photocopy room.
There are ten copies for student use in the photocopy room and we've recently added two color copiers.
The system for copying uses cards, not coins.
You can buy a photocopy card from the technician in charge of the photocopying room.
The Audio-Visual Resource is between the Reference section and the photocopy room.
You can come in here if you wish to listen to a tape or watch one of the library's videos.
We have a large collection of movies in different languages here.
Next to the photocopy room, you will see the stairs to Level 2.
Beside the stairs are the restrooms for this floor .
To go up to the other levels of the library you have to use the lifts.
In the center of this level, behind the Catalog section ,you can see two conference rooms.
You can work on group projects in the conference room without disturbing anyone , so there's a conference room on each level of the library.
Next to the restrooms, we come to our Closed Reserve room.
As most of you probably know , it is a collection of books that are in high demand so they are on restricted circulation.
If a book is on Closed Reserves section ,you can only borrow it to use within the library for three hours at a time.
Next to our Closed Reserve room is a small study room for teachers only.
The lift is between the entrance and the student lockers .
Okay , that's the end of the tour of this level of the library.
I'll leave you to look around yourselves .
Now you can go up to the other levels of the library and if you need any further help please ask the librarians.