9 Education System in British Columbia, Canada( Part 2)
Now listen to the second part of the talk on the education system in British Columbia, Canada , and complete the notes below.
Write no more than three words for each answer.
There are public that is government-funded and private that is not government-funded universities , colleges and institutes in British Columbia.
Public elementary and secondary schools are free.
But a public colleges , institutes , universities and ESL for adults at school district continuing education centers charge fees.
Many students work part-time or work in the summers  to earn money.
The BC government gives loans to many students who need financial help .
The government also pays the fees and sometimes the living expenses for low-income students in some programmes.
There are six public universities, 16 public colleges and three public institutes in British Columbia.
Universities give degrees in many fields , such as arts , science, medicine or law.
Universities do research and offer post-graduate degrees such as a Master's degree or a doctorate.
Public colleges offer first -and second -year university courses .
Some colleges give full university degrees.
Colleges and technical institutes also have many job-training programmes, such as accounting , nursing , or auto mechanics.
British Columbia has many private colleges , business schools ,  and technical schools .
Some are very good, but others may not be.
Check carefully before you register.
The fees are sometimes higher than at public colleges.
There are many English as a Second Language(ESL )classes available for adults to learn to speak , read , and write English.
Most immigrants are eligible for a free government-sponsored ESL classes under the British Columbia Settlement and Integration Programme.
Other people can attend a full-time or part-time class at a college or public school.
They charge fees , but the provincial government may help pay the fees for many low-income people.
Immigrant settlement agencies , community groups , and churches provide free or low-cost classes in some areas.
There is often a waiting list for all of the above classes.
Many private English schools and private tutors also teach English .
Some are very good, but others may not be.
They are often more expensive than classes in public schools and colleges.