9 Applying for a Tennis  Class.
You are going to hear a conversation between a student and a tennis instructor.
Listen to the conversation in fill in the form below.
Good morning .
Good morning. What can I do for you?
I'm Jack Nelson. I'd like to apply for the beginner's tennis class .
Oh , fine . You need to complete some forms first .
Well , let's get some details . Would you please spell your last name , Jack?
OK ,N-E-L-S-O-N , Nelson , Jack Nelson.
All right, Mr. Nelson. Where do you come from? I can tell you are not British .
No . I'm a Brazilian.
I see . How long have you been in the UK?
I have been here only two weeks .
What do you do?
I'm a college student .
A college student  , OK .  What do you study at college?
I study Computer Science .
That's a nice subject. I think you will have a really good chance of getting a good job after you graduate.
Yes, I think so .
Where do you live now ?  My home address...
Your present address .
All right . I live in Flat 5 , 23 Smith Road, London, W 5 .
23 Smith Road , OK . Do you have a telephone number?
Yes, 5347889.
5347889.  Good . Mr. Nelson , would you like the beginner's class?
Yes. That's right .
Have you ever played tennis at home ?
No , never.  I really want to learn.
I see.
By the way , how much does it cost?
it really depends . You see we have two beginner sessions.
One is two months long and the other is a three-month session.
I prefer the longer one.
That would be 90 pounds . Do you have a student card ?
Yes. What for ?
Well, you can get a discount if you are a student .
You will get one third off the normal price with a student card.
That's great. Here's my student card .
Your number is V 5634968 ?
Yes, that's right .
OK, you pay only 60 pounds for the class .
Here you are .
Thanks. When would you like to begin the class ? This afternoon?
Yes, why not? When does it start this afternoon?
4:30 .
That suits me . My lecture will finish at 4:00 .
OK. Let me take your blood pressure ...
OK , Jacket . Your pressure is 120 over 75 , and that's fine.
When was your last complete physical examination?
About a month ago , before I came to the UK .
Good . Do you have any back or knee problems?
No, I'm in good health . I used to play football at home.
It's very good . Here is the timetable.
Please remember , every Friday afternoon you have a tennis class . Your first lesson will start at 4:30 this afternoon.
OK, I'll be there at 4:30 this afternoon. Thank you very much .
See you this afternoon.