9 British Newspapers
You are going to hear a talk about British newspapers .
Listen to the talk and choose the correct letter A- C . Now listen to the talk.
Good morning, everyone . Today I'd like to talk about British newspapers.
Visitors to Britain are sometimes surprised to learn that newspapers there have such a large circulation.
National papers circulate throughout the whole country and they can be delivered everywhere at the same time.
The circulation of national papers is more than eight million.
There are two types of national papers , "quality papers" and "popular papers" .
The "quality newspapers" are often held up  as an example of impartial journalism ,
e.g.  The Daily Telegraph , The Times , The Guardian , The Independent and Financial Times .
The news often has a different angle to it.
Popular papers are often more sensational , e.g. The Sun , Daily Mail , Daily Mirror and Daily Express.
These newspapers usually impress newspapermen even more because they sell about four million copies every day .
As we know , Englishman love to read newspapers.
You often see them reading newspapers on buses , in the tube and at bars.
They are thirsty for news.
British families generally buy a newspaper every morning and frequently two or three on Sundays.
Besides national newspapers, local newspapers sell almost as many copies .
Local newspapers have a weekly circulation of 13 million.
Almost every town and country area has one.
These papers are written almost entirely for readers interested in local events : weddings , deaths , council meetings and sport , and the content is naturally influenced by the kind of community they serve.
Editors prefer to rely on a small staff who all know the district well.
A great deal of local news is regularly supplied by clubs and churches in the neighborhood and does not get out of date as quickly as national news.
If there is no room for it in this week's edition, an item can sometimes be held over until the following week.
Editors must never forget that the success of any newspaper depends on advertising.
They're usually anxious to keep the good will of local businessmen for this reason.
Local newspapers do not often comment on problems of national importance and editors rarely take sides on political questions.
But they can often be of service to the community by expressing public feeling on local issues .
A newspaper can sometimes persuade the council to take action to provide better shopping facilities , improve transport in the area or preserve local monuments and places of interest.
These papers often sound rather dull and it seems surprising that they all make a profit.
But for many people in small towns and villages, the death of someone known to them or the installation of traffic lights at a busy corner nearby can sometimes be more important than a disaster in a foreign country.