10. How to Select a Subject for a Research Paper (Part 2)
You are going to hear the second part of the talk on how to select a subject for a research paper .
Listen to the talk and write no more than three words for each answer . Now listen to the second part of the talk and answer the following questions.
I have just talked about the first step of selecting a subject.
Now , let's move to the second step , that is to consider your parameters.
If you were asked to develop your own subject for a research paper , there are four factors you must consider :
1 . Time  .
The amount of time you have to write influences every writing situation ,  so you have to select a subject that you can complete in the time allotted.
It's crucial to allocate your time carefully from the day you get the assignment.
Before you plunge into the process , start by making a plan or timetable.
2.  Length
The length of the paper is also a factor in your choice of topics.
It obviously takes much longer to write a 50-page research paper than to write a 10-page research paper.
Weigh this consideration as you select a subject.
3. Research.
The type of research you use also determines the subject you select.
For instance, if your assignment specifies that you must use primary sources such as letters and interviews , you might not wish to do a paper on Shakespeare , since relatively few primary sources are available and they are difficult to read .
4. Sources.
The number of sources you must use and their availability is also a factor in your choice of the subject.
If you don't have an extensive library in your area , it might be harder for you to get the material you need.
I n this case , you might want to consider a subject that requires more primary sources such as experiments , interviews, etc.
Here are some guidelines to make the process easier.
Consider your purpose .
With the research paper , your purpose is to convince so keep your purpose in mind as you weigh the suitability of various subjects.
If you cannot slant the subject to be persuasive , it is not a good choice for a research paper.
Select a subject you like.
If you have a choice , try to select a subject that interests you  .
Since you will be working with the subject for weeks and even months, you will find writing your research paper much more enjoyable if you like the subject matter.
Be practical.
Writing a research paper is challenging enough without making the task that much harder for yourself.
Beware of "hot" subjects.
Some "hot" subjects often lack the expert attention that leads to reliable information , such research papers get stale very quickly;
sometimes the issue can seem out-dated even before you finish writing the paper.
The media, especially newspapers , magazines , radio ,TV shows , and websites , can be an excellent source of research paper subjects.
Consider your audience.
As you select the subject , always focus on your audience , the person or people who will be reading your paper.
Recognize that not all questions have answers.
When you write a research paper, you were attempting to find an answer to the question you have posed or the one given to you .
Remember that not all research questions lead to definitive answers.
Dealing with questions that don't have definitive answers can make your paper provocative and intriguing.
All right , any questions so far?