10 A  Story of Galileo.
You are going to hear a story about Galileo .
Listen to the story and choose the correct letter A- C . Now listen to the story.
Good morning, everyone . Today I'd like to tell a story about Galileo.
Galileo was a famous Italian astronomer.
He was born on February 15 , 1564.
He went to school at Vallombrosa , which is a place near Florence, Italy.
He tried to learn science there, but he did not like it.
He went to the University of Pisa to continue  his studies.
He became a professor of mathematics when he was at the age of 25.
His free expressions of opinion won him such unpopularity that he had to resign.
In 1592 he went to Padua as a professor of mathematics, where he made a series of discoveries.
Most of the scientists believed Aristotle said that heavy things fall faster than light things.
This remained true until the time of Galileo.
Galileo did not believe it.
He made an experiment.
There is a famous tower at Pisa.
It does not stand straight up , but leans a little more each year .
Some scientists believe that it will soon fall down.
Galileo climbed to the top of the leaning tower , and from there he dropped two weights.
One of them was heavier than the other, but they reached the ground at the same moment.
The scientists who were watching were very surprised -- this did not agree with Aristotle's rule.
Galileo believed that scientists ought always to make  experiments .
He said that they ought not only to   sit in   university and talk ; they ought to do something .
They ought to watch  the result of their experiments , and   describe them honestly .
Then they could learn more about science .
Many people of that time believed that the earth never moved .
The other planets and the sun appeared to move around the earth , and they believed that the earth was the center of the universe.
Ptolemy had taught this many years before , and it appeared to be true.
Nobody knew that the earth was an unimportant planet.
Copernicus was an astronomer and a scientist who had studied the planets and the stars .
His ideas were new.
He said that the earth moved round the sun , and that it was not the center of everything.
He put these ideas into a book but he hid the book.
Nobody could read it until Copernicus died.
Many years later, Galileo read it and believed it.
He said that the earth was moving round the sun , and this made a lot of people angry .
They believed that the earth was too important to move .
They said that it must be the center of the universe.
Galileo got into trouble and he had to say that he was wrong, but he knew that he was right.
Galileo made many other experiments, but he also made some telescopes.
When he pointed a telescope at the moon, he saw some hills there.
He also saw some of the millions of stars in the universe -- more than anyone had ever seen.
In 1637 Galileo's eyes failed , and he could not see anything through his telescope.
Galileo return to Florence, where he spent his remaining years, becoming blind in 1637.
Five years later, he died . The world then lost a great man.