PART 2
Directions:
You will hear a question or statement and three responses spoken in English.
They will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Select the best response to the question or statement and mark the letter (A), (B), or (C) on your answer sheet.
(M-Au) Who’s the new accountant?
(W-Br)
(A) Her name is Jee-Soo.
(B) We’re behind schedule.
(C) Yes, they’re from last month
(M-Cn) You already booked your flight, didn’t you?
(M-Au)(A) No, I’ll do it tonight.
(B) I read that.
(C) Just a suitcase.
(W-Am) What still needs to be done before the grand opening?
(W-Br) (A) Outside the store.
(B) Yes, it’s still on Friday.
(C) I have a checklist.
(M-Cn) When will you hear back about your interview?
(W-Br) (A) Yes, I agree.
(B) By telephone.
(C) In a week or so.
(M-Au) Do you want to walk in the park or at the indoor track?
(W-Am) (A) It’s a bit hot today.
(B) I’ll keep track of it.
(C) My favorite pair of shoes.
(M-Au) Which supplier do you use for fruits and vegetables?
(M-Cn) (A) Every once in a while.
(B) In the supply closet.
(C) The one on Edgewood Street.
(W-Br) Where can I find an employee-referral form?
(W-Am) (A) I think they’re in Jan’s office.
(B) Seven job candidates.
(C) Thanks for letting me know.
(W-Br) Who’s managing the bookstore tomorrow?
(M-Cn) (A) Mostly history and art books.
(B) At ten A.M.
(C) I just posted the staff schedule.
(M-Au) Should we ask the waiter to bring us some water?
(W-Am) (A) For about an hour.
(B) Sure, when he comes back.
(C) No, I haven’t.
(W-Br) Why did you rearrange the tables in the boardroom?
(M-Au) (A) Eighteen chairs.
(B) I’ll have some coffee, thanks.
(C) Because I had to make more space
(W-Am) I’d like to move to the city, but it’s really noisy.
(M-Au) (A) The bus’ll be here soon.
(B) OK, I’ll turn them off.
(C) My neighborhood is pretty quiet.
(W-Am) Who came up with our new slogan?
(W-Br)(A) It went pretty well.
(B) This escalator goes down.
(C) Someone on the marketing team.
(M-Cn) Excuse me, do you have this shirt in red?
(W-Am)(A) What size do you wear?
(B) She went to that store, too.
(C) A thirty-day return policy
(W-Br) This is the best Italian restaurant in town.
(M-Cn)(A) Satoko is traveling in September.
(B) It’s where I take all of my clients.
(C) Pasta and a salad.
(M-Au) How far along are you on the quarterly report?
(W-Am)(A) I’m almost finished with it.
(B) That’s a good idea.
(C) It’s not very far from here
(M-Cn) Aren’t you attending the employee awards ceremony tomorrow?
(M-Au) (A) The position has been filled.
(B) That event’s next week.
(C) Two hundred people attended.
(W-Br) That photocopy machine is broken, isn’t it?
(M-Au)(A) He’s a member of the board.
(B) You’re right—it needs to be replaced.
(C) I prefer working in the mornings.
(W-Br) Some of us are going out for dinner after we finish this paperwork.
(W-Am)(A) Can we get this to go, please?
(B) Sorry, I have some other work to do.
(C) The newspaper’s on my desk.
(M-Cn) Don’t we have to review Joshua’s presentation?
(M-Au)(A) Yes, we were introduced.
(B) It’s a fantastic view.
(C) He’s given that presentation before.
(W-Am) Did Marcus create this advertisement?
(M-Cn)(A) They give financial advice.
(B) No, it’s Frieda’s design.
(C) I’ll be in a meeting all afternoon.
(W-Br) How do you change your password on the new system?
(M-Cn) (A) Unfortunately, they didn’t pass.
(B) I haven’t used the new system yet.
(C) Let’s change the ink in the printer.
(M-Au) Do you want to hire one or two interns for the summer?
(W-Br)(A) The second-floor conference room.
(B) They both are, I think.
(C) The budget’s quite small this year.
(M-Cn) Didn’t we select an image for the newsletter already?
(W-Br)(A) We did, but I don’t like it.
(B) A few pages long.
(C) What type of compute
(M-Au) I really enjoyed the jazz festival last weekend.
(W-Am)(A) Tickets will be available online.
(B) There were so many great musicians.
(C) We probably won’t be able to.
(W-Br) Are you going to the lawyer’s office for a meeting, or for something else?
(M-Cn)(A) Yes, the door on your right.
(B) Just dropping off some forms.
(C) It’s a good law firm.