PART 4
Directions:
You will hear some talks given by a single speaker.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speaker says in each talk.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter (A), (B), (C), or (D) on your answer sheet
The talks will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
(W-Am) Now, I'd like to discuss the next issue of our travel magazine, which will focus on traveling on a budget.
One of the articles will be about free mobile applications that make vacationing easier and cheaper.
So, your first research assignment is to look into the latest free apps that provide travel information
things like local accommodations or public transportation.
Please send me the names of the apps you find by the end of the day.
Tomorrow morning I'll be assigning each of you at least two apps, and I expect you to spend the morning writing a short report on them.
Who most likely is the speaker?
(A) A software developer
(B) A magazine editor
(C) A hotel manager
(D) A travel agent
What is the talk mainly about?
(A) A travel itinerary
(B) A corporate merger
(C) Computer upgrades
(D) Work assignments
What does the speaker want the listeners to do tomorrow morning?
(A) Write some reports
(B) Buy airline tickets
(C) Fill out some time sheets
(D) Visit some local attractions
(M-Cn) Hi, Katrina! It’s Steven, the coach of the Greentown Lions basketball team.
Listen, I just took a look at the schedule for basketball court reservations for next month.
We’re scheduled to use the courts from four to five P.M.
The thing is… many of my players work in the afternoon, so they can’t get to the courts until quarter to five.
You’ve got the courts reserved from five to six…
Could you call me back when you have the chance? Thanks!
What kind of team does the speaker coach?
(A) Tennis
(B) Basketball
(C) Volleyball
(D) Badminton
What does the speaker say about his players?
(A) They practice every day.
(B) They will play in a competition.
(C) Most of them live far away.
(D) Many of them have jobs.
Why does the speaker say, “You’ve got the courts reserved from five to six”?
(A) To confirm an appointment
(B) To express surprise
(C) To request a change
(D) To congratulate a colleague
(W-Br) Gather round, crew! I have an important announcement to make before we continue our work on the building project today.
The clients have asked us to speed up construction.
The only way we can finish by April twelfth is by having half the crew work on Sundays.
Tell me if you’re available. You know the procedure…
you can sign up for overtime shifts in my office.
I need to update the clients on this by the end of the day. Thanks for all your hard work.
And for those of you who agree to work on Sundays, lunch will be provided.
That’s the company’s way of showing our appreciation!
What field does the speaker most likely work in?
(A) Catering
(B) Construction
(C) Manufacturing
(D) Real Estate
What does the speaker imply when she says, “I need to update the clients on this by the end of the day”?
(A) She is unable to attend an event.
(B) She needs more current data.
(C) She disagrees with a supervisor's suggestion.
(D) She wants employees to decide quickly.
What will the company do for some employees?
(A) Provide a meal
(B) Sign a certificate
(C) Arrange transportation
(D) Schedule extra days off
(W-Am) Good evening. Tonight I’ll be talking about a new initiative by GS Incorporated,
a leading manufacturer of mobile phones and electronic accessories.
As part of its commitment to sustainability,
GS Incorporated announced today that it has started to package its products in a more environmentally friendly way.
Now, they come in boxes made entirely of recycled materials.
After a short commercial break, I’ll be interviewing a representative from GS Incorporated about what inspired these changes.
What does GS Incorporated manufacture?
(A) Commercial vehicles
(B) Cleaning supplies
(C) Fashion accessories
(D) Electronic devices
What has GS Incorporated recently started to do?
(A) Use environmentally friendly packaging
(B) Sell some products internationally
(C) Collaborate with another company
(D) Donate to charitable organizations
What will the listeners hear after the commercial break?
(A) A song
(B) A weather forecast
(C) An interview
(D) A traffic update
(M-Cn) Welcome to our new-employee information session.
Today’s session will be about important company policies you need to be aware of.
Let’s start with reporting missed workdays.
You’ll need your ID number from your badge to log in to the Attendance Plus online application.
There, you can report your absence.
If the online application isn’t working for some reason and you can’t report your absence by eight-thirty A.M.,
you need to leave a message for your supervisor at 555-0123. Any questions?
What is the speaker mainly talking about?
(A) A new project
(B) A company policy
(C) Employee performance targets
(D) Advantages of teamwork
According to the speaker, why do the listeners need to use an online application?
(A) To view a list of clients
(B) To manage group work
(C) To report an absence
(D) To upload an identification photo
What should the listeners do if an online application is not working?
(A) Leave a message for a supervisor
(B) Call technical support
(C) Ask a colleague for assistance
(D) Reboot a computer
(W-Am) Thanks for tuning in to today’s health show.
I have a question for my listeners.
Have you been wanting to lower your sugar intake but just can’t resist that sweet snack at the local café?
Today, I’ll teach you about an eating program that will stop your cravings permanently.
I used this program to lower my sugar intake, and it worked!
In fact, this program could help you change any eating behavior in one month. That’s not a lot of time!
The first step is setting goals.
So take out a piece of paper and write down three eating habits you’d like to change.
What is the main topic of the broadcast?
(A) Eating habits
(B) Stress management
(C) Exercise routines
(D) Sleep issues
Why does the speaker say, “That’s not a lot of time”?
(A) To express concern about a deadline
(B) To complain that a broadcast is too short
(C) To emphasize the benefit of a program
(D) To compliment some coworke
According to the speaker, what should the listeners do first?
(A) Ask a friend for help
(B) Make a list of goals
(C) Create a timeline
(D) Purchase a handbook
(M-Cn) Welcome to Newport News at Seven.
Don’t forget that next Saturday, the Newport Technology Museum will open its new interactive Robotics exhibit.
This exhibit will feature many different robots, and visitors will be able to talk to them, play with them, and even learn from them.
Students from the Robotics department at nearby Newport University will be at the museum on Saturday
to show you how to interact with robots and explain how they work.
But make sure to buy your tickets in advance from the museum’s Web site. This event will be packed!
What will happen at the Newport Museum on Saturday?
(A) A parking area will be unavailable.
(B) An award will be presented.
(C) A gift shop will give discounts.
(D) An interactive exhibit will open.
What does the speaker say about some Newport University students?
(A) They raised money for some equipment.
(B) They published a research paper.
(C) They will give demonstrations at the museum.
(D) They should submit job applications to the museum.
According to the speaker, what should the listeners do in advance?
(A) Read about robots
(B) Download a mobile app
(C) Register for a class
(D) Buy tickets
(M-Au) Hello, Mr. Kanno. This is Scott Jansen calling from KR Investors Group.
Thanks for coming in last week for an interview for the market analyst position.
We were very impressed with your past work experience,
and we’d like to offer you the job.
Now, as I’d mentioned, you’ll have to relocate from Chicago to Vancouver.
I’m confident you’ll like living there. It’s a great city, with a lot to do and see.
So congratulations, I’m looking forward to speaking with you again.
Oh, and please keep in mind that KR Investors Group won’t be open next week.
Why is the speaker calling?
(A) To set up an interview
(B) To finalize travel arrangements
(C) To offer employment
(D) To discuss an upcoming workshop
What does the speaker say the listener will be required to do?
(A) Apply for a passport
(B) Revise a document
(C) Provide letters of recommendation
(D) Move to another city
What does the speaker say will happen next week?
(A) His company will be closed.
(B) A holiday party will be held.
(C) Registration will begin.
(D) Some prices will be lowered.
(W-Br) I’d like to start our meeting by discussing our advertising efforts for our new running shoes.
The company president has asked our department to focus on online advertising.
So, take a look at the chart I passed out.
It shows popular types of Web sites with advertising space for sale.
Although social media sites get the most visits,
I think we should go with the type that attracts our target audience.
Although these sites only have about 3,000 users per day,
the people who visit those sites will likely be interested in our product
So our next step is to plan the designs for those advertisements.
Let’s break into groups to discuss that.
In what department does the speaker most likely work?
(A) Technology
(B) Advertising
(C) Customer service
(D) Training
Look at the graphic. Which type of Web site does the speaker recommend?
(A) Finance
(B) Travel
(C) Fitness
(D) Social Media
What will the listeners most likely do next?
(A) Review a policy
(B) Research competitors
(C) Visit a Web site
(D) Discuss some designs
(M-Au) Hi, this is a message for the manager of H.W.’s Sandwiches.
I’m standing outside your store— it’s seven-thirty, and it’s closed.
I don’t see a sign on the door, but I’m looking at your Web site on my phone, and it says that you should be open tonight.
I’m disappointed…
I’ve made a special trip to your restaurant this evening to try the new spicy chicken sandwich for dinner,
and I even have a ten percent off coupon that expires today.
Will you still accept it if I come back tomorrow?
I have some time and I’d really like to use the coupon.
Please let me know. This is John,
at 555-0179.
Look at the graphic. When is the speaker leaving the message?
(A) On Monday
(B) On Wednesday
(C) On Thursday
(D) On Sunday
Why does the speaker leave the message?
(A) To apologize for a mistake
(B) To express disappointment
(C) To show appreciation
(D) To communicate a decision
What does the speaker request?
(A) An updated menu
(B) A job application
(C) A flexible delivery time
(D) An extension to use a coupon