PART 1
Directions:
For each question in this part, you will hear four statements about a picture in your test book.
When you hear the statements, you must select the one statement that best describes what you see in the picture.
Then find the number of the question on your answer sheet and mark your answer.
The statements will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Statement(C),"They're sitting at a table,"
is the best description of the picture,
so you should select answer(C)and mark it on your answer sheet.
(A) The man is plugging in a computer.
(B) The man is drinking from a cup.
(C) The man is opening a window.
(D) The man is adjusting a chair.
(A) The woman is using a ladder.
(B) The woman is lifting a container.
(C) The woman is pushing a cart.
(D) The woman is placing some tools in a box.
(A) A man is closing the top of a copy machine.
(B) A man is installing some tiles.
(C) A woman is handing some paper to a man.
(D) A woman is putting on a sweater.
(A) A lawn is being mowed.
(B) A tree is being cut down.
(C) The men are shoveling some soil.
(D) The men are driving a vehicle.
(A) Some food is being carried on a tray.
(B) A waiter is writing on a notepad.
(C) A waiter is serving some beverages.
(D) Some customers are giving their menus to a waiter.
(A) A bench is being replaced.
(B) A lamppost is being repaired.
(C) Some bricks are stacked in a pile.
(D) Some boats are floating in the water.