PART 3
Directions:
You will hear some conversations between two or more people.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speakers say in each conversation.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter (A), (B), (C), or (D) on your answer sheet.
The conversations will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
(M-Cn) Ms. Chin, Ms. Frankel, I'm sorry that the gallery hasn't been looking very tidy lately.
I've been so busy with all the artwork that we've been receiving that I have't had time to focus on cleaning.
(W-Br) Oh, I know. The gallery's been so busy that it's hard to keep up with sweeping and dusting the main display area.
(W-Am) Why don't we hire a cleaning service?
(M-Cn) Sure. I can call a few local cleaning services to get some prices.
(W-Am) That'd be great. Thanks for bringing this up.
Where do the speakers most likely work?
(A) At a movie theater
(B) At a construction firm
(C) At an art gallery
(D) At a furniture store
What problem are the speakers discussing?
(A) A display area is not clean.
(B) An appliance is broken.
(C) Some bills are not paid.
(D) Some materials are missing.
What will the man most likely do next?
(A) Request a recommendation
(B) Reserve a rental car
(C) Look for some replacement parts
(D) Contact some local companies
(W-Am) Excuse me. I don't live in the city, but I'm here for a conference.
Can you tell me which bus goes to the conference center at forty-first and Stockton Street?
(M-Au) That's the number eight bus. The conference center is just two stops down.
(W-Am) Oh good, thanks.
I'm a little concerned about arriving late for the opening ceremony.
(M-Au) Oh, it shouldn't take long at all to get there.
And if you're going to be here for a few days, I suggest buying a weekly pass.
It's good for unlimited travel around the city.
Why does the woman say she is visiting the city?
(A) To see a museum exhibit
(B) To attend a conference
(C) To receive an award
(D) To look at some real estate
What does the woman say she is concerned about?
(A) Being unable to get a ticket
(B) Booking a hotel room
(C) Having a wrong address
(D) Arriving late for an event
What does the man recommend doing?
(A) Looking at a map
(B) Checking an online site
(C) Buying a weekly pass
(D) Calling a friend
(W-Br) I'm glad we chose this restaurant for lunch. The food is absolutely delicious.
(W-Am) I agree. My whole meal was excellent.
(W-Br) You know, this might be a good place to have George's retirement dinner.
(W-Am) Why don't we ask the server if we can make a reservation for a large group? Here he comes now.
(M-Au) Can I get you two anything else?
(W-Am) Actually, we have a question.
A colleague is retiring, and we're interested in having his dinner here.
Do you have space for an event like that?
(M-Au) Of course! We have a large private dining room.
And for your convenience, you can order your food online ahead of time.
What do the women like about the restaurant?
(A) The food
(B) The atmosphere
(C) The service
(D) The prices
What event do the women want to have at the restaurant?
(A) A client meeting
(B) A department luncheon
(C) A birthday party
(D) A retirement celebration
What convenience does the man mention?
(A) Wireless Internet access
(B) Free delivery
(C) Advance ordering
(D) Party-planning consultations
(W-Am) Hello, Daniel? It's Kumiko calling.
I'm still on my way to the office, so I'm afraid I won't be able to go over our presentation materials with you.
(M-Au) Oh—The meeting starts soon.
(W-Am) Well, the train I'm on has been delayed.
I'm sure you could lead the presentation without me.
(M-Au) Sure, I can do that if I have the handouts.
Where can I find them?
(W-Am) They're printed out, and I put them in a blue folder in my top desk drawer.
(M-Au) Great. I'll go get them now.
Why does the man say, “The meeting starts soon”?
(A) To refuse an offer
(B) To ask that participants be seated
(C) To announce a schedule change
(D) To express a concern
What does the woman suggest that the man do?
(A) Arrange some transportation
(B) Purchase some supplies
(C) Set up a video call
(D) Take over a presentation
What does the man ask about?
(A) How long a meeting will be
(B) Where to find some documents
(C) How to contact a colleague
(D) When a train will depart
(M-Cn) Hi, welcome to Gold Pyramid Clothing.
(W-Br) Hi, I bought a shirt here for my son,
but unfortunately, he doesn't like the color.
What's your return policy?
(M-Cn) As long as it hasn't been more than 30 days since you purchased the item,
and you have a receipt, you can receive a full refund.
(W-Br) Hmm, actually, I seem to have lost my receipt.
(M-Cn) Well, then I can't give you a refund. But, you can exchange it for a different color.
(W-Br) OK, I'll do that then.
(M-Cn) Sure! I think we have that shirt in stock in black and green.
Where most likely are the speakers?
(A) At a bookstore
(B) At an art supply store
(C) At a clothing retailer
(D) At a supermarket
Why is the woman unable to receive a refund?
(A) She purchased a discounted item.
(B) She has lost a receipt.
(C) A store has changed a policy.
(D) A product has been damaged.
What does the man suggest?
(A) Exchanging an item
(B) Speaking with a manager
(C) Returning at a later time
(D) Applying for a rewards program
(M-Cn) Hey, Amanda. How was the Business Technology Seminar?
(W-Am) Oh, it was great!
I saw a software application for corporate accounting that was really interesting.
Instead of using many different spreadsheets,
this application integrates invoices, online payments, and expense tracking, all in one.
(M-Cn) Hmm, we'd really benefit from switching to a system like that.
(W-Am) I agree. I'm preparing a demonstration of the application to present at the management meeting on Wednesday.
I think we should seriously consider using it.
What event did the woman recently attend?
(A) A technology seminar
(B) A client dinner
(C) A department celebration
(D) An employee orientation
What did the woman find interesting at the event?
(A) A volunteer opportunity
(B) A building layout
(C) An accounting application
(D) A guest speaker's profile
What will the woman do on Wednesday?
(A) Take some time off
(B) Give a demonstration
(C) Present an award
(D) Participate in a training session
(W-Br) I just heard about the company's plan to open a second housewares store.
They want to put it in the Centerville Mall,
but I don't think we'd get enough business selling household items there.
(M-Au) Well, the marketing team has done the research.
(W-Br) I thought people mostly shopped for electronics at that mall, not decorative items for the home.
(M-Au) That's a good point.
But we'll just have to wait and see what the board of directors decides at their meeting in January.
What plan is the company considering?
(A) Expanding its inventory
(B) Updating its filing system
(C) Hiring a new marketing director
(D) Opening another location
What does the man imply when he says, “the marketing team has done the research”?
(A) He is happy to not be assigned a task.
(B) He disagrees with a colleague.
(C) He does not want to hire more staff members.
(D) He hopes an advertising campaign will begin soon.
What will take place in January?
(A) A job interview
(B) A board of directors meeting
(C) A storewide sale
(D) A focus group test
(M-Cn) Hello, are you checking in for an appointment?
(W-Am) Actually, I had my annual physical with Dr. Perez here last Thursday,
but I need to have him sign this form.
(M-Cn) That's right, I remember you.
What do you need the form for?
(W-Am) Well, I'm starting a new job next month, and I need to give this form to my new employer.
(M-Cn) OK. Dr. Perez is currently with a patient.
I can give him the form to sign when he's finished. Would you like to have a seat while you wait?
(W-Am) Could I come back for it later? I need to pick up a friend from the airport.
(M-Cn) Sure.
Why is the woman at the doctor’s office?
(A) To get a prescription
(B) To have a form signed
(C) To review some test results
(D) To make an appointment
What does the woman say she will do next month?
(A) Start a new job
(B) Cancel a subscription
(C) Join a fitness center
(D) Take a vacation
Why does the woman say she cannot wait for the doctor?
(A) She has a lunch reservation.
(B) She has to take a phone call.
(C) She is late for a presentation.
(D) She needs to pick up a friend.
(W-Br) Hello. I'm interested in purchasing software that can improve photographs I've uploaded to my computer.
But I don't want to spend more than fifteen euros.
(M-Cn) OK—we have lots of photo-enhancing software here you might like.
What exactly are you looking to do with it?
(W-Br) Hmm… well, most of the pictures I've taken aren't very clear.
I really want software that can sharpen the lines of each image so they're easier to see.
(M-Cn) Certainly, let's take a look at a few options over here.
I'm sorry… You'll probably have to spend more than fifteen euros, but these products will help you get the job done.
What does the woman want to purchase?
(A) A camera
(B) A computer
(C) Some software
(D) Some art supplies
What would the woman like to improve?
(A) The speed of her Internet
(B) The quality of some photos
(C) The price of a service
(D) The design of a product
According to the man, what will the woman have to do?
(A) Visit a different store
(B) Spend more than expected
(C) Speak with a technician
(D) Keep a receipt
(M-Au) Kondo Landscaping, how can I help you?
(W-Br) Hi. I'm calling because my company wants to have a patio area built behind our office.
Could you build a space where about 25 employees could sit outside during their lunch break?
(M-Au) Yes, we build patios.
We usually start outdoor projects in the spring.
We don't build patios in the winter because the cold weather can damage the materials we use.
(W-Br) OK, let me go over this with my manager. Thanks.
What does the woman ask the man about?
(A) Building a patio
(B) Renovating a lobby
(C) Installing a light fixture
(D) Constructing a parking garage
Why does the man recommend delaying a project?
(A) His company is very busy.
(B) Materials could be damaged.
(C) Equipment costs may decrease.
(D) A building permit is needed.
What will the woman most likely do next?
(A) Call another company
(B) Consult with a manager
(C) Read some online reviews
(D) Send photographs
(W-Am) Welcome to the Department of Motor Vehicles. How can I help you?
(M-Cn) Hi, I want to sign up to take a driver's license test.
(W-Am) To register is 30 dollars.
(M-Cn) Wow, that much? I thought it'd be less expensive…
Uh… when can I take it?
(W-Am) We give the driver's license tests every week, but they're all booked until… July twelfth.
(M-Cn) Oh, I'll be on vacation in July.
(W-Am) We have an opening on August third.
(M-Cn) Good. I'll register for that.
(W-Am) OK, I'll just take your information for your driver's license, but you'll need to go pay at the next window.
What is the man surprised about?
(A) The size of an office
(B) The length of a line
(C) A course requirement
(D) A registration fee
What does the man say he will do in July?
(A) Take a vacation
(B) Start a training course
(C) Buy a new car
(D) Move to another city
Look at the graphic. Which window does the woman send the man to?
(A) Vehicle Inspections
(B) Driver's Licenses
(C)Cashier
(D)Insurance Information
(W-Br) Have you seen the logo Mark created? I think it's perfect for our restaurant.
(M-Au) He sent me a picture of it this morning. It'll look great on our employee T-shirts.
(W-Br) Speaking of the T-shirts… have we decided where to have them printed?
(M-Au) I've already called a few companies. Most won't print fewer than 50 shirts,
but there's one place that doesn't require so many to be ordered at once.
(W-Br) Great. Let's go with that one. We only need twenty to start out.
(M-Au) OK. I'll order them right away.
That way we'll get them in time for our restaurant's grand opening on May fifth.
What did Mark send the man?
(A) A logo
(B) An invoice
(C) A contract
(D) A menu
Look at the graphic. Which printing company will the speakers most likely choose?
(A) Klinton Apparel $6.25 minimum order 55
(B) Elwan Tees $6.10 75
(C) Meecher Designs $6.50 20
(D) Pheeps Prints $6.35 50
According to the man, what will happen on May 5 ?
(A) A corporation will host a dinner.
(B) A restaurant will hold a contest.
(C) A clothing sale will take place.
(D) A new business will open.
(M-Cn) Hi, Caroline. Did you see the chart that was posted in the break room?
I really like the nutritional program that Human Resources is promoting.
(W-Br) Me too. I think eating certain foods is important not just for our health; it also makes us more productive.
(M-Cn) I agree. For example, I've been told that I need more vitamin A,
and the chart shows me one fruit that is rich in vitamin A.
(W-Br) Of course, it would also help if the cafeteria offered healthier options…
(M-Cn) Isn't there a suggestion box at the cafeteria? Maybe we could submit some ideas.
What do the speakers mainly discuss?
(A) Break-room renovations
(B) Updated cafeteria hours
(C) A healthy-eating program
(D) Results of an employee survey
Look at the graphic. Which fruit will the man most likely add to his diet?
(A) Watermelon vitamin A
(B) Banana vitamin B6
(C) Orange vitamin E
(D) Papaya vitamin C
What does the man suggest doing?
(A) Ordering some lunch
(B) Providing feedback
(C) Attending a seminar
(D) Seeing a health-care provider