PART 4
Directions:
You will hear some talks given by a single speaker.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speaker says in each talk.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter (A), (B), (C), or (D) on your answer sheet
The talks will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
(America) W
Hello, this is Sylvia Chen.
I recently purchased a camera from your online shop.
Unfortunately, when the camera arrived the lens was scratched.
I want to bring it to the post office this afternoon to return it for an exchange,
but l'd like to speak to someone from your company before I mail it.
You see, I'm moving to a new house next week, so the replacement will have to be shipped to my new address.
Please call me back so I can be sure your shipping department will send the camera to the correct address.
What is wrong with the camera?
(A) It is missing a part.
(B) It is an older model.
(C) It is too heavy.
(D) It is damaged.
Where does the speaker want to go this afternoon?
(A) To a real estate agency
(B) To a camera store
(C) To a post office
(D) To a warehouse
Why does the speaker request a return call?
(A) To change an order
(B) To arrange a rental
(C) To confirm an address
(D) To get driving directions
(Britain) W
Now, turning to local news,
the annual Art Walk festival will be held this Saturday.
The festival offers residents the chance to discover local art galleries and to talk with gallery owners and artists.
The walk starts at the Clareton City Hall,
where you‘ll receive a map showing all the participating galleries.
And this year, for the first time, food from local restaurants will be available at each gallery.
Information about parking for the event can be found on the city’s Web site.
What is happening this weekend?
(A) A marathon
(B) An art festival
(C) A music concert
(D) A community picnic
Where are listeners instructed to go first?
(A) To a ticket booth
(B) To a stadium
(C) To a city hall
(D) To a county park
What details can be found on the city’s Website?
(A) Parking information
(B) Rain dates
(C) A map of the city
(D) A list of musicians
(Australia) M
Hello Alborada Apartments residents.
Thank you for letting me speak at tonight's tenant meeting.
My name is Jay, and I'm the new maintenance manager for the complex.
In my first few days as maintenance manager,
I've realized that many of you are having problems with the air conditioning in your apartments.
So my crew and I will be coming around to each apartment over the next three weeks to inspect all the air conditioning units and decide which ones need to be replaced.
The good news is, the pool will be opening for the summer next week.
Don't forget to collect your pool passes from the main office on Monday.
Who is the audience for the talk?
(A) Hotel guests
(B) Maintenance staff
(C) Apartment residents
(D) Garden club members
What problem does the speaker mention?
(A) The pool needs to be painted
(B) A reservation has been lost
(C) Some air conditioners are not working
(D) The hotel restaurant is closed
What does the speaker remind listeners to do on Monday?
(A) Check out on time
(B) Sign a new lease
(C) Make minor repairs
(D) Pick up passes
(Britain) W
Hi, everyone.
Today we have some urgent business to attend to.
I just received word that Moon-Hee Lee will be making a visit to our store tomorrow.
Lee is our regional manager, who oversees five stores in the area including this one.
Now, it's very important that we give her a good impression,
so I'm requesting that everyone stay a bit late today to help get the store cleaned and organized.
And, since you'll be working extra hours today, you can each select a morning to take off next week.
Just let me know which day you choose to come in later, so I can update the schedule.
Who is Moon-Hee Lee?
(A) A regional manager
(B) A new employee
(C) A health inspector
(D) A prospective client
Why does the speaker ask listeners to stay late?
(A) To process a large order
(B) To wait for a shipment to arrive
(C) To attend a workshop
(D) To prepare the store for a visit
What does the speaker offer the listeners?
(A) A company dinner
(B) A cash bonus
(C) Some time off
(D) Some merchandise
(Australia) M
This is Scott Durlin, and you‘re listening to Scotts Money Advice on WYBR Radio Ninety-one,
where we discuss how to handle all types of money and home-budget topics.
I want to let listeners know, that as of today,
you can download audio files of past broadcasts of our show
from my newly updated Web site, www.Scottsadvice.com.
This is in addition to the usual links and interactive features on topics from the show.
And I always like to hear from you,
so please e-mail me any money questions you might have,
I'll be sure to answer them on the air.
Now let's return to our discussion of what to do when buying a car with our guest, Nina Robinson.
What is the main topic of the radio show?
(A) Financial planning
(B) Web site design
(C) Interior decorating
(D) Car repairs
What has recently become available online?
(A) Step-by-step instructions
(B) Audio recordings
(C) Product reviews
(D) Free estimates
Why does the speaker say, "And I always like to hear from you"?
(A) To arrange for a guest speaker
(B) To ask for technical help
(C) To thank his audience for their interest
(D) To encourage listeners to contact hi
(America) W
Good evening!
I'm so glad you all could make it tonight to celebrate our company's expansion.
When I first started this greeting card company,
it was only a small team of three people struggling to make our business work.
And now we have twenty full-time employees,
we've expanded our distribution, and we even have a new, much larger office space.
So please, before you leave the banquet, pick up your gift bag.
It's my personal token of appreciation to thank all of you for your contribution to our company’s success.
What is being celebrated?
(A) The completion of some renovations
(B) The retirement of a colleague
(C) An award for community service
(D) The growth of a company
Who most likely is the speaker?
(A) A lead architect
(B) A business owner
(C) A current client
(D) A conference coordinator
What are employees asked to do before they leave?
(A) Meet a public official
(B) Be in a group photograph
(C) Make a donation
(D) Collect a gift
(Canada) M
Hi, Mariko, this is Francois Duchamp calling from Human Resources.
We're supposed to begin posting the laboratory assistant position this Friday.
But, I don't know, have you seen the interview questions we use?
Since you supervise the laboratory employees,
I'd really be interested in your opinion of them.
It would be great if you have some time today to talk about this.
I'm about to go to an early lunch, but I’ll be at my desk until five o'clock this afternoon. Thanks.
What position is being advertised?
(A) Program coordinator
(B) Administrative assistant
(C) Laboratory worker
(D) Human Resources director
What does the speaker imply when he says, "have you seen the interview questions we use"?
(A) He is confirming an assignment.
(B) He has misplaced some forms.
(C) He is concerned about some questions.
(D) He wants the woman to lead an interview.
Why does the speaker want to meet with the woman?
(A) To introduce an applicant
(B) To ask for her opinion
(C) To offer her a promotion
(D) To plan an orientation
(Britain) W
Hi, this is Laura Dunn.
I'm calling about a catering order you just delivered for our corporate luncheon this afternoon.
l just realized that one of the food trays we ordered wasn't included
we're missing the pasta.
Now, between the sushi and the chicken dish, we’ll have enough food
but I wanted to make sure we get a refund on the pasta.
Could you please process the refund to the same credit card I used to place the order?
Thanks and have a nice day.
What event does the speaker mention?
(A) A training session
(B) A company lunch
(C) A cooking contest
(D) A grand opening
What is the problem?
(A) An item is missing
(B) A delivery was late
(C) A discount was not applied
(D) A staff member is unavailable
Look at the graphic.
How much money will the speaker be refunded?
(A)Sushi $160
(B)Rice and chicken $140
(C)Pasta $135
(D)Assorted fruit $50"
(Canada) M
Good morning and thanks for inviting me to this board meeting.
You asked me to find ways for our company to become more environmentally friendly,
so here's what I came up with.
Here are four options for desktop management software.
After business hours,
when most computers are not in use, these programs will automatically turn off our computers, saving costs and energy.
All are compatible with the hardware we use,
and the projected savings are comparable for all four software systems
However, only one has a system for backing up data in an emergency.
So that's the one I recommend.
Where does the talk most likely take place?
(A) At a press conference
(B) At a company meeting
(C) At a job-training session
(D) At a technology conference
What does the company want to do?
(A) Hire a consultant
(B) Purchase new desktop computers
(C) Become more environmentally friendly
(D) Have employees work at night
Which option does the speaker recommend?
(A) $450 back-up system
(B) $350 no back-up system
(C)  $450 no back-up system
(D) $500 no back-up system
(Britain) W
Welcome to your first day at The Harling Company!
Your role in handling customer inquiries over the phone will be crucial to our sales.
Here's your training calendar…
So, today, we'll get you set up and we'll teach you the basics of the job.
Then, for the rest of the week you'll be trained one-on-one by your manager.
You'll practice answering the phones and receive feedback at the end of the week on your interaction with the customers.
You'll really enjoy working with your managers,
you'll see.
.they’re great!
Oh, and one more thing:
the company president wants to meet all of you.
So she organized a team lunch to welcome you all.
What are the listeners training to be?
(A) Computer technicians
(B) Restaurant chefs
(C) Assembly line workers
(D) Customer service representatives
According to the speaker, what will the listeners enjoy doing?
(A) Working with managers
(B) Touring the company
(C) Meeting with customers
(D) Using new equipment
Look at the graphic On what day will the listeners meet with the company president?
(A) Tuesday set up and basics
(B) Wednesday practice&team lunch
(C) Thursday practice
(D) Friday practice&receive feedback