PART 1
Directions:
For each question in this part, you will hear four statements about a picture in your test book.
When you hear the statements, you must select the one statement that best describes what you see in the picture.
Then find the number of the question on your answer sheet and mark your answer.
The statements will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Statement(C),"They're sitting at a table,"
is the best description of the picture,
so you should select answer(C)and mark it on your answer sheet.
(A)she's wearing headphones.
(B)She's opening a drawer.
(C)She's holding a microphone.
(D)She's pushing a button.
(A)They're using laptop computers.
(B)They' re exchanging business cards.
(C)One of the men is putting on a sweater.
(D)One of the men is moving a chair.
(A)She's pointing toward a building
B)She's handing the man an umbrella
C They're greeting each other
D)They re walking side by side
A)A chalkboard is being erased
B)Some people are attending a presentation
C) A man is leaning against a doorway
D)All of the seats are occupied
A)Passengers are exiting an airport terminal
(B)An aircraft is taking off from a runway
(C)Pieces of luggage are lined up on the  pavement
D)A staircase has been positioned next to an  airplane
A) Fresh vegetables are being chopped on a  cutting board.
B)Food is being cleared from a counter.
C) Bowls have been stacked on a kitchen shelf.
D)Some cookware has been left on a stove.