PART 3
Directions:
You will hear some conversations between two or more people.
You will be asked to answer three questions about what the speakers say in each conversation.
Select the best response to each question and mark the letter (A), (B), (C), or (D) on your answer sheet.
The conversations will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
(Canada) M：Hi Karen, I wonder if you can help me.
I have a doctor’s appointment tomorrow afternoon,
so I need someone to take my shift at the restaurant.
(Britain) W：No problem – I can do that.
Would you cover my shift next Monday evening in exchange?
Of course. I’ll let the supervisor know about the change in schedule right now
What does the man say he has to do tomorrow?
(A) Have his car fixed
(B) See a doctor
(C) Submit a report
(D) Plan an event
What do the speakers agree to do?
(A) Collaborate on a project
(B) Meet at a restaurant
(C) Exchange contact information
(D) Trade work shifts
What will the man probably do next?
(A) Notify a manager
(B) Cancel an appointment
(C) Train new staff
(D) Clean a work area
(Canada) M
(America) W
Hi Ken, hi Julio!
How did the art gallery opening go last weekend?
Was the client happy with the marketing materials?
(Canada) M
Alfredo? He was very pleased.
He said he thought the brochures we designed were one of the main reasons for such a great turnout.
(Australia) M
And it's worth checking out the gallery when you have some time.
I’m sure Alfredo would be happy to give you a tour.
(Canada) M
Yes, the place is so bright and modern,
with a fantastic collection of local works of art.
(America) W
You know, I'm taking a vacation in that area in February. I'II make a point of visiting him.
What were the men doing last weekend?
(A) Conducting a tour
(B) Training new employees
(C) Attending a gallery opening
(D) Designing a building
What type of work did the speakers do for Alfredo?
(A) They created marketing materials
(B) They furnished an office space
(C) They revised a workflow procedure
(D) They made a financial investment
What does the woman plan to do in February?
(A) Hire new staff
(B) Relocate to another city
(C) Attend a conference
(D) Take a vacation
(Britain) W
Hi.
I'm Petra Barlow.
I have an interview for a position in the accounting department here at Houseman Incorporated.
(Canada) M
Hello, Ms. Barlow.
Let me check in the computer.
While I do that,
would you put on this visitor's badge so it's easy to see?
(Britain) W
Yes, of course.
I'm supposed to meet with Helen Wade in Meeting Room 2B.
Is that right?
(Canada) M
Actually,
it looks like there was a last-minute change.
You’ll be meeting in Room 12A instead.
It's down that hallway and to your left.
(Britain) W
Thanks a lot.
Why is the woman at Houseman Incorporated?
(A) To register for a class
(B) To have a business lunch a
(C) To lead a seminar
D) To attend an interview
What does the man ask the woman to do?
(A) Wait in the lobby
(B) Update an application
(C) Wear a badge
(D) Provide photo identification
What does the man say has changed?
(A) The location of a meeting
(B) The date of an event
(C) The length of a session
(D) The number of participants
(Canada) M
Good afternoon.
I currently subscribe to your Gold Plan satellite television package.
I'd like to switch to the Platinum Plan because there are some new movie channels that I'd like to watch.
(America) W
Of course, I'd be happy to I help you upgrade your subscription.
Could you spell your last name for me so that I can look up your account?
(Canada) M
Yes, it's K-W-A-N.
When should I expect to have access to the extra channels?
Your account will reset tomorrow at six A.M.,so you'll be able to watch them first thing in the morning.
I just want to remind you that an extra fifteen dollars will appear on your next monthly bill for this expanded service.
What is the conversation mainly about?
(A) A television service
(B) A newspaper subscription
(C) A radio program
(D) A theater production
What does the woman ask for?
(A) A bank balance
(B) The Web-site address of a business
(C) The spelling of a name
(D) A serial number
According to the woman, when will the change take effect?
(A) Today
(B) Tomorrow
(C) Next week
(D) Next month
(Britain) W
Hi, I’ve just unloaded the last box of bathroom tiles.
The whole delivery's in your warehouse now.
Would you be able to sign for them? I need a signature.
(Canada) M
I'm sorry, this is my first day on the job.
I’d better check with the warehouse manager to see if I'm allowed to do that.
(Britain) W
Should I wait here while you check?
(Canada) M
Actually,
if you wouldn't mind moving your truck, that’d be great, since we're expecting some other deliveries shortly.
What does the woman request?
(A) An invoice
(B) A map
(C) A signature
(D) A replacement part
What does the man say he has to do?
(A) Find his security pass
(B) Talk with a supervisor
(C) Unlock a door
(D) Check inventory
What does the man ask the woman to do?
(A) Return later
(B) Lower a price
(C) Move a vehicle
(D) Remove some boxes
(Australia) M
OK, Ms.
Torres, I have your price estimate.
To have the whole exterior of your house painted,
including the fence, will cost you five thousand dollars.
(America) W
That's quite a bit more than we expected.
And actually Colgate Painting said they would do it for four thousand dollars…
(Australia) M
Well,
the cost of paint and supplies is included in the price I quoted you, so we really offer a very good deal.
(America) W
That's a bit of a relief.
If there are no other charges, we’ll probably be able to stay within our budget.
What are the speakers discussing?
(A) An appliance warranty
(B) Blueprints from a designer
(C) A building permit
(D) A home improvement project
Why does the woman say, "And actually Colgate Painting said they would do it for four thousand dollars”?
(A) To clarify a request
(B) To negotiate a price
(C) To offer some help
(D) To recommend a service
Why is the woman relieved?
(A) Some work will be completed on time
(B) A cost estimate includes supplies
(C) A selected item is in stock
(D) Experienced workers will be on-site
(America) W
Thabo and Michiko,
I need help designing some pamphlets for our evening business courses.
I'd like to have them ready before the end of April.
(Britain) W
Sure.
Should we take a look at the ones from last year or make them different?
(Australia) M
You know,
I think the pamphlets last year had too many details.
People can get dates and times from the Web site.
(America) W
I agree.
Lets focus on the skills that people will learn in each class.
(Australia) M
OK.
I’ll come up with a rough version of the text for the pamphlet by tomorrow and e-mail it to you.
Then, next week we can start working on the design.
What are the speakers planning to advertise?
(A) Evening classes
(B) Job opportunities
(C) An online store
(D) A printing demonstration
According to the man, what was the problem with last year’s pamphlets?
(A) They were not ready on time
(B) They were the wrong size
(C) The information was too specific
(D) The contact number was missing
What does the man say he will send the woman?
(A) Free product samples
(B) A list of participants
(C) A draft of a document
(D) A revised schedule
(Australia) M
Hello.
I’m calling because I’d like to temporarily stop my mail delivery.
I’m going to be out of town for the next two weeks.
(Britain) W
Certainly We can hold your mail here at the post office for you.
But you’ll need to put in your request at least a day before you leave.
(Australia) M
That sounds great.
Do I need to come into the office and complete a form?
(Britain) W
No, actually,
you have to submit the "hold mail” form on our Web site.
Why is the man calling?
(A) To make plane reservations
(B) To reschedule mail delivery
(C) To get directions to a shop
(D) To order some envelopes
According to the woman, how far in advance should the man make his request?
(A) One day
(B) Two days
(C) One week
(D) Two weeks
What is the man required to do?
(A) Pay a fee
(B) Confirm an address
(C) Give an account number
(D) Submit an online form
(America) W
Hello, Oscar - it's Tanya from the Cardona Museum.
Unfortunately our budget's been cut, so we’ll have to delay some of the renovations we’ve asked you to do.
(Australia) M
Ah - that's too bad.
Do you know which parts of the project you’d like to put off?
(America) W
Well, I know we talked about adding a library wing on the west side of the building - but that’s very expensive.
So, if we don't make that addition, that's all we may need to cut.
(Australia) M
You know, that’s not a bad idea.
Let's see how much you'd save if I take the library out of the renovation proposal.
I'll e-mail you a revised estimate this afternoon.
What is the problem?
(A) A deadline has been moved up
(B) Some funding has been reduced
(C) Some materials have not been delivered
(D) An architect is not available
Which part of the renovations will likely be postponed?
(A) A library addition
(B) Some roof repairs
(C) An electrical system upgrade
(D) Some window replacements
What does the man mean when he says, “that’s not a bad idea"?
(A) He would like to hear more suggestions.
(B) He prefers the original plan.
(C) He agrees with the proposed solution.
(D) He has a better idea.
(Canada) M
Hi, Gabriella.I wanted to talk to you about using the new online time reporting system.
A lot of people have been asking about it.
(Britain) W
Yes, well, I've been very busy.
But I am planning the training session for early next week
That should make it quite clear to everyone.
(Canada) M
OK.
But isn't there any written documentation?
(Britain) W
What do you mean?
(Canada) M
You know, a guide that staff can follow in the meantime.
(Britain) W
I don’t think that's necessary.
I'll have everyone go through the steps with me in the computer lab.
Then they'll know exactly what to do.
It's very simple.
What are the speakers discussing?
(A) Drafting a contract
(B) Working extra hours
(C) Using a new time reporting system
(D) Revising a vacation policy
What does the man imply when he says, “A lot of people have been asking about it”?
(A) Staff are confused about a procedure.
(B) People have heard that a workshop is interesting.
(C) Staff are waiting for a new assignment.
(D) A vacation calendar has not been posted yet.
What does the woman plan to do?
(A) Lead some training
(B) Ask for assistance
(C) Take some time oil
(D) Author a manual
(Australia) M
Hi.
I'm going on a trip, and
I'm interested in buying an electronic reader so I don't have to carry books with me.
(Britain) W
Well,
we carry all major brands of e-readers here - I'm sure we can find the right one for you.
(Australia) M
Oh, good.
(Britain) W
Are you looking for any special features?
(Australia) M
It has to be user-friendly - I'm not very good with technology.
I just want to read books - not watch movies or play games.
(Britain) W
In that case, I'd suggest this one It's very easy to download e-books onto it, and it holds up to three hundred books.
Here,
let me show you how it works.
Where does the conversation most likely take place?
(A) At an electronics store
(B) At a public library
(C) At a movie theater
(D) At a travel agency
What is the man concerned about?
(A) Repair fees
(B) Difficult technology
(C) Warranty terms
(D) Screen size
What does the woman offer to do?
(A) Call a supervisor
(B) Provide a demonstration
(C) Exchange an item
(D) Apply a discount
(America) W
Hi, I'd like to have this dress cleaned.
I'm going to a conference at the end of this week, and Id like to take it with me.
Oh, and. Can you tell me how much it'll cost?
(Canada) M
Let me take a look…
it's going to be twelve dollars.
(America) W
Oh, that much?
Your sign out front says dresses can be cleaned from seven dollars and up.
(Canada) M
Well yes, but it's the material the dress is made of.
We have to use special cleaning products to make sure we don't damage the fabric
(America) W
OK.
(Canada) M
I can rush the service and have it to you by Wednesday evening.
Does that work?
What does the woman say she will do later this week?
(A) Attend a dinner
(B) Go to a conference
(C) Host a celebration
(D) Visit her family
Look at the graphic.
What is the dress made of?
(A) Cotton
(B) Wool
(C) Mixed synthetics
(D) Silk
What does the man say he will do?
(A) Print a receipt
(B) Expedite a service
(C) Send a confirmation
(D) Schedule an appointment
(Australia) W
Hi, Jim.
I hear you're going to the jazz concert on Friday.
Can I ask you a favor?
(Canada) M
Sure, what do you need?
(Australia) W
A few of us from the graphics department are also attending the concert,
but we have a meeting until six o'clock on Friday.
Since there are no assigned seats,
we were wondering if you could save a few places for us.
(Canada) M
That shouldn't be a problem.
I don't have any meetings on Friday afternoon, so
I plan to get there when the doors open.
How many should I reserve?
(Australia) W
Hmm.
I'm not sure yet if Eduardo is joining us.
Why don't I send him an e-mail right now, and I'll let you know how many seats to save.
What does the woman ask the man to do?
(A) Record a performance
(B) Save some seats
(C) Check the time of a meeting
(D) Arrange for transportation
Look at the graphic.
When does the man plan to arrive at the concert hall?
(A) At 5: 30 P.
M.
(B) At 6: 00 P.
(C) At 6: 30 P.
M.
(D) At 7: 00 P.
What will the woman do next?
(A) Print a confirmation
(B) Send an e-mail
(C) Approve a purchase
(D) Request contact information