PART 2
Directions:
You will hear a question or statement and three responses spoken in English.
They will not be printed in your test book and will be spoken only one time.
Select the best response to the question or statement and mark the letter (A), (B), or (C) on your answer sheet.
What time does the movie start tonight?
we're moving on Saturday.
At seven o'clock.
It was in the theater.
Where is the furniture department?
On the tenth floor.
A sofa and two chairs.
I took it apart.
Who led the budget presentation yesterday?
Yes, I read it.
The main conference room.
Ms. Varma did.
Would you rather drive to the game or take the train?
Let's drive
On Thursday, I believe.
Please take it with you.
When are they announcing the winner of the competition?
At the radio station.
By the end of the week.
A gift certificate.
Would you like to make a donation to the arts council fund?
No thanks, I have some.
He's very generous.
Sure, here's five dollars.
Who chose the restaurant for the company banquet?
Maybe once last year.
Someone from Human Resources.
Next Friday evening.
Are you going to accept the management position?
Everyone else.
They’re in finance.
Yes, I start June first.
Which spaces are designated for visitor parking?
Only for two hours.
It's alright, I'il take the bus.
The ones with yellow signs.
Wouldn't you rather meet in a conference room?
It usually doesn't.
A three o'clock meeting.
It would be quieter.
Do you know who this jacket belongs to?
Yes, very expensive.
No, where did you find it?
It won't take too long.
Let's work through lunch to finish the project
A sandwich and an apple.
But I really need a break!
It was this morning.
Why does Dr Yang need another lab assistant?
I didn't know he requested one.
At least three years’ experience.
Yes, we visited the new lab.
Dr. Martinez will be free this afternoon.
I’ve been here before.
What about tomorrow morning?
The pharmacy is just downstairs.
Can I write an article on the festival for Tuesday’s newspaper?
You're right; it's too long.
The deadline has passed.
He's at the museum now.
Don’t you want to see the apartment?
West of Main Street.
We had to order a part.
I've found a place already.
Should I order the supplies now, or wait until next week?
A total of seventy-five dollars.
Actually, I already sent the order.
It's in the supply closet.
How should I store these photographs?
Mateo is responsible for that.
From the company picnic.
Yes, the staff is very helpful.
Where should I set up the equipment for the photo shoot?
That's scheduled for next week.
It was taken in Amsterdam.
I got it from the electronics store.
You haven't seen Jennifer today, have you?
I saw her a while ago.
I don't have any yet.
No, my name's Janet.
Could you help me find the Murphy Company file?
I'm fine, thanks.
He left a while ago.
I don't work on that account.
Why has the workshop been canceled?
About twenty minutes ago.
In Room Fourteen.
Because many people couldn't attend.
You've already signed the contract, haven't you?
I'Il do it right now.
Yes, I turned it off.
What does the sign say?
I thought the professional development training was really helpful.
I'd be happy to help.
That was my experience, too.
Sure, I'll take care of it.
Where did you make the dinner reservation?
Tomorrow at twelve-thirty.
Didn't you make it?
For fourteen people.